好吧，我给你看的最后一段视频
language I made, ugly but works.
And we compiled this into this weird binary format.
然后把这个二进制文件传递给这个叫做invoice的程序，它执行我们的
program.
在上一个视频中，我还向您展示了这个二进制格式的开头
triggers a buffer overflow and overwrites the return pointer on the stack.
在那一点上，您可能认为我们的程序只是shellcode，所以汇编程序
code, that we inject and then jump to, with the buffer overflow.
But that is not even possible, because the stack is not executable.
所以即使我们不能注入实际的汇编程序指令来执行，我们还是
able to execute my programs.
And at this point it’s pretty clear, that this is possible thanks to return-oriented-programming.
So let’s examine how this works.
But I warn you.
You really need to get your brain into an abstract philosophical thinking mode.
This will get weird.
也许你以后得重新看一遍，也许结账时会更“正常”
Return Oriented Programming tutorials and then come back to this.
但如果你能看到这段视频，我想它会让你更加深入地了解
for you.
So just try...
Anyway.
Let’s head in.
So in x86 assembler there is an instuction called “call”.
And call actually does two things.
首先，它推送返回地址（即呼叫后的地址
instruction) on the stack.
And then it changes EIP, the current instruction pointer, to the call destination.
So the CPU continues execution there.
Now when we in C call a function, this will be compiled to an assembler call instruction.
But to understand return-oriented-programming, you have to forget this.
Ignore the concept of calling functions.
只需记住，此指令会在调用指令后立即推送地址
onto the stack, and then set instruction pointer to the target address.
And the return instruction behaves in the same way.
YES ret is compiled from a return in C. But forget this connection.
ret只是弹出一个地址，我们称之为返回地址，从堆栈中取出并设置
instruction pointer back to that.
And “pooping a value” from the stack is also already again an abstract interpretation.
它的字面意思是，它查看堆栈指针寄存器，在地址之后，
takes that value.
And then it increments the stack pointer register.
It increments because the stack grows downwards.
So if we shrink it, when we POP a value, we increase it.
So it gets closer to the highest address again.
Anyway.
This is what ret does.
它在堆栈寄存器指向的地方取这个值，增加堆栈指针地址，
然后使用它得到的值来设置指令指针。
(in quotation marks).
So this was lesson one.
忽略指令的名称或它的典型含义和典型用法，只需理解
what the instruction itself does.
So again, remember what the “ret” (the return) instruction does.
First look at the stack register, follow this address and take that value.
Increment the stack pointer.
Set the instruction pointer to that value.
Done.
Now let’s think about something else.
机器执行指令意味着什么？
A CPU is a piece of hardware that executes instructions.
这些指令是机器代码或汇编代码，对吗？
从抽象的意义上讲，这是如何工作的？
Well there is memory, where instructions are stored, and this memory has addresses.
然后CPU有一个指令指针寄存器，其中包含指向内存的地址
with the next instruction to execute.
So if it’s 0, it will execute this.
And then it does whatever this instruction is defined to do.
Not that important what this instruction exactly does.
但通过执行任何指令，指令指针只需递增并向前移动。
to point to the next instruction.
然后执行，指令指针将更新为指向下一个
one.
And so forth.
当然，这会随指令而改变，如跳转、调用或返回，其中
pointer is directly updated.
But you get it.
从抽象的意义上讲，计算机是一种给出指令的计算机
or executes those instructions.
So the CPU is a machine implemented in hardware.
But of course there are also virtual machines.
So machines implemented on top of our CPU machines.
And for example the JVM, the Java Virtual Machine behaves in the same way.
It is a machine.
所以在内存的某个地方有字节码，而软件，JVM有一个指令
指向下一指令的指针，或称为程序计数器PC的指针，或
there called opcode.
当JVM执行一个操作码时，它还必须更新程序计数器并移动
it to the next one.
Here I looked up the source code for that.
这里是openjdk源代码，您可以看到更新“pc”和“continue”
宏，它将当前操作码的大小（或长度）添加到程序中
counter, so this moves it forward.
Like the CPU would increment the instruction pointer.
So this is lesson two.
A machine in an abstract sense is simple.
There is memory that holds code or instructions.
机器指向代码，接受指令，执行它，然后更新
the program counter to point to the next one.
那么F'与面向返回的编程有什么关系？
Well last video I also introduced the concept of a weird machine.
Somehow this invoice program implemented a weird machine.
我知道，这个概念是非常混乱的，但请原谅，它在
moment.
如果这个发票程序实现了一个奇怪的机器，而你编程了那个奇怪的机器
with a technique called return-oriented-programming, then you should ask yourself now.
包含指令的内存在哪里，指向的指令指针在哪里
对于这些指令，以及执行任何定义的指令的逻辑在哪里
做什么？
Well, luckily we have some example programs, and we can debug this weird machine with GDB.
Let’s load the invoice program into GDB and let’s learn how it executes.
我不想再解释缓冲区溢出，请检查我的二进制攻击
playlist for that.
But when you are familiar with it, you know that we overwrote stuff on the stack.
如果查看add_invoice函数，可以找到危险函数gets（），其中
cause the buffer overflow.
So we can set a breakpoint here, and we set one at the return.
Then let’s run the binary and as an input we pass in the helloworld.binary.
And we know now that input triggers the buffer overflow.
So here we hit the breakpoint at the gets.
If we execute the gets and examine th stack, we can find all of our input here.
Here are all the As that fill up the buffer.
And then we have these randomly looking, but actually carefully chosen values after it.
But let’s go forward to the return instruction.
So now we are about to execute the return, and please remember what return means.
它查看堆栈寄存器中的地址，所以这里这个地址指向这个内存，
so this is the stack and that’s the top element.
返回指令现在将该值作为地址，并设置指令
pointer to it.
And at the same time increments the stack pointer.
So let’s do that.
Single step forward.
ANd now let’s compare before and after the return.
It did exactly what we expected.
The stack pointer register was incremented from 0x18 to 0x20, so move 8 bytes forward.
And the instruction pointer got set to the value previously on top of the stack.
Btw... when we execute a “ret” we also often use the phrase “we return into &lt;something&gt;”.
不管我们说“我们回到了”，说“我们回到了”还是说“我们
continued execution here”.
It’s all the same.
Don’t get confused by the term “return”.
You know what the ret instruction really does.
It simply takes a value from the stack and sets the instruction pointer to it.
Anyway.
那么现在发生了什么？
我们的指示指针指向哪里？
It points here...
To this assembler code.
A pop rdx and a pop rbx.
然后又回来了？
So this means it takes one value from the stack and puts it into rdx.
Increments rsp again.
Then takes the next value on the stack and moves it into rbx.
Increments rsp and then we are at the return again.
现在返回获取堆栈上的下一个值，并将指令指针设置为
it.
那么它现在在哪里继续执行呢？
Okay.
现在我们到了？
Here we have a pop rdi.
So it takes the next value on the stack, moves it into rdi.
And then comes ret, which takes the next value and sets the instruction pointer to it.
我们现在在哪里？
Now we execute a move.
We move edx, into the address pointed to by rdi.
还记得我们设置EDX的时候吗？
The pop RDX at the beginning, set the value of EDX to a value we had on the stack.
还有rdi，我们现在写的地址，我们在堆栈上也有，并把它放入rdi
with a pop RDI.
想想这段代码现在做了什么！
我知道它看起来很奇怪，但它只是把我们想要的值移到一个地址
we specified.
我们将一个值移入RDX，然后将一个地址移入RDI，然后编写EDX值
to the address RDI points to.
Now look at the source code of the hello world program.
这里的代码说我们将字符串“hell”移动到变量中，当然是4个字节。
4.
然后将变量4存储在内存位置
1.
这只是另一种说法，我们移动字符串，或者4个字节，“地狱”
into rdx.
And then we move rdx to a memory location we specify in RDI.
哪个内存位置，以及将字符串“hell”转换为四个字节
my compiler program does.
I know, maybe that is a bit too confusing, maybe better just ignore my compiler shenanigans.
But if think about what we did.
We executed these few instructions that move a value into some memory location.
And we did that by using super weird instructions, which we usually refer to as “gadgets”.
To perform this memory write, we used three gadgets.
首先我们使用“pop rdx，pop rbx”小工具，然后使用“pop rdi”小工具，然后使用“mov”
gadget”.
看看这些小玩意有什么共同点？
They all end with a return instruction.
Now bend you mind.
把我们刚才看到的情况，试着把它融入到机器执行的概念中去。
instructions.
First, we have memory, that is our stack.
On there we had all these addresses and values.
以一种奇怪的方式，堆栈指针是我们的指令指针，对吗？
我们的奇怪机器基本上是从一个返回操作码开始的，它取了第一个地址
on the stack and continued CPU execution there.
Then the stack pointer pointed to the next value, we popped it and moved it to the next.
Pooped another value moved it to the next.
And then came another return which took the value and let the CPU execute code there.
Moving the stack again to the next value.
因此，在某种程度上，栈上的地址，当我们有返回时，定义指令
处理程序，对吗？
你可以说这个地址实际上是操作码，执行一个pop的指令
rdx and then a pop rbx.
另一个小工具，这里的地址，是将EDX移动到
address of rdi.
这与x86汇编程序“调用”指令的实际方式不一样吗？
means we push an address on the stack and set the instruction pointer to the given destination.
这种“调用”x86指令与我们怪异的机器小工具有何不同？
不是！
Both define some action, what it does, and then the machine moves to the next instruction.
CPU通过递增指令指针来执行此操作，Java虚拟机执行此操作。
通过简单地增加程序计数器，我们的奇怪的机器通过增加
the stack pointer.
I know, these gadgets are super weird instructions.
以及每个程序，这取决于它包含多少代码以及函数的类型
写在那里，编译器把代码放在内存中的什么地方，改变了什么类型的代码
of gadgets are available.
使用小工具ropgadgets，我们实际上可以列出所有小工具，因此汇编程序片段
have this pattern of a few instructions followed by a “ret”.
基本上，这些都是我们可以用来实现我们想要的任何东西的奇怪指令
on this weird machine.
I know it’s crappy.
没有人说它必须像CPU或Java虚拟机那样是一个经过深思熟虑的机器。
Machine.
But it’s enough to basically perform any kind of computation.
对我来说，足够收集一些看起来有用的小工具，并构建一个编译程序来翻译
this text representation to actual addresses that point to those gadgets.
这就是为什么每个程序都有这样一个漏洞，不小心制造了自己的漏洞。
weird machine.
每个易受攻击的程序都有自己的指令集，它是
gadgets.
And it’s own initialisation code that setups that weird machine.
Basically the code that triggered our vulnerability in the first place.
So writing such an exploit.
本质上是通过触发缓冲区来设置和实例化一个奇怪的机器
overflow.
然后我们用一个ROP链，一组链接的小工具来编程这台奇怪的机器。
由于x86“ret”指令
together with the stack works.
And what we can program is just bound by our creativity and availability of useful gadgets.
但是如果你有大量的小工具，你可以理解你可以实现
ANYTHING you want.
You just chain these small assembler snippets together to build anything.
在一次攻击中，你通常试图创建一个远程外壳或其他东西，但实际上它可以
be just a regular program.
就像我创建了这些ROP链，例如将两个数字作为输入，
adds them together, and prints the result.
And that’s it.
That is return oriented programming explained in a super confused way.
I know, this is maybe not the best ROP tutorial.
但是有太多的“普通”教程，我只是想尝试一些不同的东西
我希望你们中的一些人在这个问题上有不同的观点
opening.
至少对我来说，这是一个令人难忘和美丽的时刻，正如你所知道的，它成为了一个口号。
for my channel.
Also I like to remind you to checkout the papers and talks I have listed in the description.
Please read them even if you didn’t understand this video.
它们也许更好，但更准确地解释了这一奇怪机器的概念。
and exploit development.
Anyway… thanks for watching and maybe checkout my Patreon and YouTube membership in the description.